<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Prashant Vaidyanathan</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hud036e253d667841def3d4af41fe46192_1097_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPselection</title>
      <link>/project/fpselection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/fpselection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Molecular biologists rely on the use of fluorescent probes to take measurements of their model systems. These fluorophores fall into various classes (i.e. fluorescent dyes, fluorescent proteins, etc.), but they all share some general properties and require equipment for data acquisition. While they all share some properties, selecting an ideal set of fluorophores for a particular measurement technology or vice versa is a multidimensional problem that is difficult to solve with ad-hoc methods. The fpSelection tool uses a set of algorithms for solving these problems efficiently to design n-color fluorophore panels that are optimized for maximal signal, minimal bleed-through, and other biological parameters for a specific fluorescent measurement instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix</title>
      <link>/project/phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/phoenix/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEC</title>
      <link>/project/gec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/gec/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSBOL</title>
      <link>/project/fsbol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/fsbol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STL Metrics</title>
      <link>/project/stlmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/stlmetrics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grid TLI</title>
      <link>/project/gridtli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/gridtli/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cello</title>
      <link>/project/cello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/cello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cello input is a high-level logic specification written in Verilog, a hardware description language. The code is parsed to generate a truth table, and logic synthesis produces a circuit diagram with the genetically available gate types to implement the truth table. The gates in the circuit are assigned using experimentally characterized genetic gates. In assignment, a predicted circuit score guides a breadth-first search, or a Monte Carlo simulated annealing search. The assignment with the highest score is chosen, and this assignment can be physically implemented in a combinatorial number of different genetic layouts. The Eugene language is used for rule-based constrained combinatorial design of one or more final DNA sequence(s) for the designed circuit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetSynth</title>
      <link>/project/netsynth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/netsynth/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clotho</title>
      <link>/project/clotho/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/clotho/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infared Tracking RC Car</title>
      <link>/project/irtrackingracingcar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/irtrackingracingcar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project consisted of a system to make an RC car autonomously follow a remote, Infrared (IR) emitting beacon. The remote beacon was built using an MSP430 microcontroller to transmit a 38KHz pulse width modulated (PWM) IR signal via an IR LED. The microcontroller, IR LED, and battery power were then soldered into a PCB board. To track the IR signal emitting from the beacon a circuit of IR receivers that demodulated the 38KHz PWM signal, arranged in a particular geometry, was built on a PCB. Finally, a Gumstix board used the output of the receiver circuit to determine the car&amp;rsquo;s position relative to the beacon and drive the car toward the beacon. The Gumstix decision algorithm was implemented in a Linux kernel module.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kocoon Baby Mote</title>
      <link>/project/kocoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/kocoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An embedded device to monitor vital signs (body temperature, pulse rate, and humidity) for infants and send real time alerts to doctors and hospital personnel to facilitate fast and precise medical response.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Scrubs</title>
      <link>/project/cloudscrubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/cloudscrubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A multi-platform electronic data storage and retrieval system to store and secure medical information for patients and allow doctors easy access to data while maintaining doctor-patient condentiality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
